When you check the output file for your program,
当你打开程序的输出文件时
you see a few 100 lines with artists.
你会看到好几百行的数据
But you would've expected millions of lines.
但你的预期是会看到几百万行
It seems to have worked for a short while,
似乎这个程序工作了一小会儿
but then it got stuck.
然后突然卡住了
In order to debug your program,
为了调试你的程序
you run the program again,
你又跑了一次程序
but this time with every other program closed,
这次你把其他无关的程序都关了
except for your system's built-in activity monitor.
除了你的系统管理器
What you see when you start your program,
当你开始跑程序时
is a small spike of activity for your storage, memory,
存储内存和CPU活动一下子就增加一些
and CPU as the first part of the data
因为第一部分的数据
is transferred from storage to memory,
从存储加载到了内存
and then processed by the CPU.
然后被CPU 处理了
After that initial spike, the CPU activity flatlines,
这之后 CPU 的活动就减落了
but the input-output known as IO,
但是内存和存储的输入/输出或者叫 IO
for the memory and storage stays near 100 percent.
增加到了接近百分之百
The CPU has some small blips of activity,
CPU 活动偶尔会小跳一下
but it's clear that your system CPU
显然你系统的存储和内存
is being slowed down by the memory and disk.
正在拖慢CPU
Here's what's going on inside your machine.
这是你电脑里的活动的过程
The program loaded nearly eight gigs of data into your memory,
程序从存储加载了大概8 G 的数据到内存
leaving almost no memory for other programs and your operating system.
导致其他程序和系统没有内存使用了
Your CPU process this data pretty quickly and pass
你的CPU处理数据非常快
the relatively small results back to memory
迅速把结果返回给内存
to be written back to the output file on disk.
然后被写入硬盘的输出文件里
This is the same as what happened
这和数据量只有4 G时
when the data was only four gigabytes.
发生的事一样
But after the first batch of roughly eight gigs was processed by the CPU,
但是当第一批差不多 8 G 的数据被 CPU 处理好后
it was ready to handle more.
它就开始准备处理下批数据了
This is when the CPU activity dropped.
这时 CPU的活动下降了很多
Unfortunately, the next batch of eight gigabytes wasn't ready yet.
但是下一批数据还有没有准备好
It's still had to be loaded from storage to memory,
它需要从硬盘加载到内存
and that's much slower.
这非常慢
If you recall, it's about 3,000 times slower
回忆一下 从硬盘加载数据
to read data from disk than to process it in the CPU,
会比CPU处理数据慢3000 多倍
and you have to do this process dozens of
而且要经过好几十次这样的过程
times to get through the entire 200 gigs of data.
才能把 200 G 的数据处理完
This is why your system seems to grind to a stop.
这就是你系统卡住的原因
It's spending most of its time moving data in and out of memory.
其实就是大部分的时间都被用来搬数据了
Most of the CPU activity is actually from coordinating this movement,
CPU 大部分活动都是在协调搬运数据
which is like context switching for your computer's brain.
就像你大脑一直在做任务切换
This back and forth is known as thrashing,
这个来来回回的过程叫做颠簸
and it can be a major problem for dealing with big data.
当数据量很大时这会成为严重的问题
But then, you remember your idea from the previous year.
突然 你想起了你去年的点子
What if you split this data into multiple pieces and email it to your coworkers?
如果你把数据拆分成多份 然后邮件给同事会快一些吗？
You email the data to 40 of your colleagues,
于是你把数据发给了 40 个同事
so each chunk is only five gigs,
所以每部分数据只有 5 G
and will fit into their memories.
这些数据就可以一下加载到内存里了
Since there's no thrashing involved,
因为不存在颠簸
they get the results quickly and email them back to you.
同事们很快就跑出了结果 然后把结果发还给你了
It still takes a long time to email the 200 gigs of data,
虽然发 200 G 数据的邮件要花很长时间
since the network is so slow.
毕竟网速太慢了
But you only have to distribute the data once
但是你只用分配一次数据
to avoid the thrashing problem completely.
这样就完全避免了颠簸问题
In fact, you could get around this problem by splitting the data
为了避免颠簸 你还可以把数据分成 80 份
into 80 pieces and sending each coworker two of them.
然后给每个同事发两份
This way, they can download their first chunk
这样 他们就可以先下载第一份
and start processing it while they download the second one.
然后在处理第一份的同时下载第二份数据
Like the previous year, you still have to deal
和去年一样 你还是会面临
with incompatible Python versions, busy colleagues,
Python 版本的兼容 同事分身乏术等问题
but this trade-off seems worth it compared to the paralysis
但和死机比起来
your laptop was facing when it tried to handle the data on its own.
利弊权衡后 这个方法还是值得一试的
It's now easier to distribute the data and process it
现在 把数据分配到多台电脑
in parallel on multiple machines.
同时处理数据就优于单台电脑了
You're now in the world of big data
欢迎来到大数据的世界